shiksha.com 2019-11-15

# Shiksha::Privacy Policy

## Introduction

We, at "Info Edge (India) Limited" herein referred to as "IEIL" and our affiliated companies worldwide, are committed to respecting your online privacy and recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") you share with us, in-line with the applicable data protection laws and regulations. 

This Policy is subject to the terms of the Site Policy (Terms of Use) of Shiksha.com and the Application. This policy applies to those who register on the Platform (as defined in the Terms of Use) provided by the Shiksha.com, in connection with use of our services, or whose information Shiksha.com otherwise receives in connection with its services (such as but not limited to contact information of individuals associated with Shiksha.com including partner colleges/ educational institutes etc.) 

Personal information (PI) - means any information relating to an identified or identifiable living person. In particular using a common identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person or any other piece of information as per applicable laws and regulations. 

## Information collection

We collect information about you or your usage to provide better services to all of our users. We collect information in the following ways: 

  * Many of our services require you to register/sign up for an account on Shiksha.com. When you do, we will ask for personal information, such as, but not limited to your name, email address and telephone number to create/update your account. 
  * To provide you additional services, we may collect your profile information such as, but not limited to education background, work experience, date of birth. 
  * We collect information about the services that you use and how you use them such as, but not limited to log information and location information. 
  * We may collect your personal information such as but not limited to bank details, passport details to assist for study abroad program which includes services like Letter of recommendation, student profile and student visa. 
  * When you communicate with Shiksha.com or its Application or use the Shiksha.com platform to communicate with other Members (such as advertisers, colleges/ institutes, etc.), we collect information about your communication and any other additional information you choose to provide. 

## Processing personal information

Shiksha.com may process your Personal Information for the following purposes: 

  * We use information collected from cookies and other technologies, like pixel tags, to improve your user experience and the overall quality of our services. When showing you tailored ads, we will not associate an identifier from cookies or similar technologies with sensitive categories, such as those based on race, religion, sexual orientation or health.
  * Our automated systems analyse your content to provide you customised search results, recommendations and specific promotions and offers
  * Send alerts and newsletter(s) to you (Provided you subscribe to the same. To unsubscribe, please visit your account settings)
  * Improving our website and its content to provide better features and services 
  * Conducting market research and surveys with the aim of improving our products and services.
  * Sending you information about our products and services for marketing purposes and promotions.
  * Preventing, detecting, investigating and prosecuting crimes (including but not limited to fraud and other financial crimes) in any jurisdiction, identity verification, government sanctions screening and due diligence checks
  * Establishing, exercising or defending legal rights in connection with legal proceedings (including any prospective legal proceedings) and seeking professional or legal advice in relation to such legal proceedings.

## Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Some of our Web pages utilize "cookies" and other tracking technologies. A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect your information about Website activity. Some cookies and other technologies may serve to recall Personal Information previously indicated by a Web user. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them.

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser, but please note that if you choose to erase or block your cookies, you will need to re-enter your original user ID and password to gain access to certain parts of the Web site and some sections/features of the site may not work.

Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clickstream patterns; and dates and times that our site has accessed. 

Our use of cookies and other tracking technologies allows us to improve our Web site and your Web experience. We may also analyse information that does not contain Personal Information for trends and statistics.

For more information about our use of cookies please refer to our Cookie Policy.

## Third Party Services

Third parties provide certain services available on Shiksha.com on IEIL’s behalf. Shiksha.com may provide information, including Personal Information, that ‘Shiksha.com collects on the Web to third-party service providers to help us deliver programs, products, information, and services. Service providers are also an important means by which Shiksha.com maintains its Web site and mailing lists. Shiksha.com will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third-party service providers are obligated to protect Personal Information on Shiksha.com behalf.

Shiksha.com does not intend to transfer Personal Information without your consent to third parties unless such transfer is required for providing relevant services or for purposes legal purposes. 

When you are in a relationship with Shiksha.com, your personal information may be transferred to geographies outside India, for the purposes mentioned in this policy or to their local service providers for support in the pursuance of such purposes. Transfers outside India are covered by standard data protection laws.

Please be aware that Shiksha.com sometimes contains links to other sites that are not governed by this privacy policy. Visitors to Our Site may be directed to third-party sites for more information, such as advertisers, blogs, content sponsorships, vendor services, social networks, etc. 

Shiksha.com makes no representations or warranties regarding how your information is stored or used on third-party servers. We recommend that you review the privacy statement of each third-party site linked from Our Site to determine their use of your personal information.

## Children

To use the Site you agree that you must be of minimum age (described in this paragraph below) or older.

In case you are resident of the European Union, the minimum age for these purposes shall be 16, however if local laws require that you must be older in order for Shiksha.com to lawfully provide the services on the Site to you then that older age shall apply as the applicable minimum age. 

In all jurisdictions outside the European Union, if you are under the age of 18 or the age of majority in your jurisdiction, you must use Shiksha.com under the supervision of your parent, legal guardian or responsible adult.

## Information Sharing 

We restrict access to your Personal Information to employees who we believe reasonably need to know/or that information in order to fulfil their jobs to provide, operate, develop, or improve our products or services. 

Shiksha.com does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or non-affiliated companies except:

  1. to provide products or services you've requested, 
  2. when we have your permission, 
  3. or under the following circumstances:

  * We provide the information to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with ‘IEIL’ under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your personal information to help Shiksha.com communicate with you about offers from ‘Shiksha.com and our marketing partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information.
  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;
  * We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of ‘Shiksha.com terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.
  * We transfer information about you if ‘Shiksha.com is acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, ‘Shiksha.com will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.
  * We share your personal information with colleges or educational institutions, etc. based on your browsing behaviour or expression of interest regarding courses, specializations and institutions who may further contact you.

"Shiksha.com" displays targeted advertisements based on personal information. Advertisers (including ad serving for example, women aged 18-24 from a particular geographic area. 

  * "Shiksha.com" does not provide any personal information to the advertiser when you interact with or view a targeted ad. However, by interacting with an ad you are consenting to the possibility that the advertiser will make the assumption that you meet the targeting criteria used to display the ad.
  * "Shiksha.com" advertisers include financial service providers (such as banks, insurance agents, stock brokers and mortgage lenders) and non-financial companies (such as stores, airlines, and software companies).
  * We may share personal information (such as name, mobile number, and email address) with carefully selected education colleges/ educational institutions based on your expression of interest regarding courses, specializations and institutions so that they may consider further marketing campaigns or recruitment measures. Some of these educational institutions may have access to your personal information to verify the status of your application or enrolment. We will inform the education institutions that they are not allowed to use your personal information for any reason other than mentioned above. Users should note however that, how these educational institutions use this data is not governed by our privacy policy. Therefore, we cannot be held responsible for how the data is utilized once it is shared with them. Educational institutions have separate policy practices for which Shiksha.com has no responsibility or liability. For further information on how such institutions use your information, please visit the applicable privacy policy of that institution. 
  * Shiksha.com works with vendors, partners, advertisers, and other service providers in different industries and categories of business. For more information regarding providers of products or services, please refer the section “Third party services” of this policy

## Retention of personal information

Your personal information processed by Shiksha.com are kept in a form which permits your identification for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal information are processed in line with legal, regulatory, contractual or statutory obligations as applicable. 

At the expiry of such periods, your personal information will be archived to comply with legal/contractual retention obligations or in accordance with applicable statutory limitation periods. 

## Personalisation of services

To the extent permitted by law, Shiksha.com may record and monitor your communications with us to ensure compliance with our legal and regulatory obligations and our internal policies. This may include the recording of telephone conversations.

## Personalisation of services

You may have the right to invoke certain rights (as per applicable laws and regulations such as GDPR) in relation to your personal information being processed by the Platform.

The Platform may be allowed by law, in particular in case of excessive or manifestly unfounded request, to charge a fee for fulfilling your request, subject to applicable conditions. 

You are legally entitled to request details of the personal information we may be holding about you. The Company provides you the ability to keep your personal information accurate and up-to-date. If at any time you would like to rectify, erase or restrict the processing of your personal information, or you would like to obtain confirmation whether or not your personal information is processed by it, access your personal information, exercise your right to data portability or withdraw your consent to processing, please contact us.

You are entitled to lodge a complaint with a competent Data Protection Authority where existing, concerning the Platform’s compliance with the applicable data protection laws and regulation.

## Confidentiality and Security

The security and confidentiality of your Personal Data is important to us and Shiksha.com has invested significant resources to protect the safekeeping and confidentiality of your personal data. When using external service providers acting as processors, we require that they adhere to the same standards as Shiksha.com. Regardless of where your personal information is transferred or stored, we take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that personal data is kept secure.

We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with the laws prevalent in India to protect personal information about you. We seek to ensure compliance with the requirements of the Information Technology Act, 2000 and Rules made there under to ensure the protection and preservation of your privacy.

## Social media

Shiksha.com operates channels, pages and accounts on some social media sites to inform, assist and engage with you. Shiksha.com monitors and records comments and posts made on these channels about Shiksha.com in order to improve its products and services. Please note that you must not communicate with Shiksha.com through such social media sites the following information: 

  * Sensitive personal data including (i) special categories of personal data meaning any information revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, and the processing of genetic data, biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person, data concerning health or data concerning a natural person's sex life or sexual orientation and (ii) other sensitive personal data such as criminal convictions and offences and national identification number ;
  * Excessive, inappropriate, offensive or insulting information towards individuals.

Shiksha.com is not responsible for any information posted on those sites other than the information posted by its employees on its behalf. Shiksha.com is only responsible for its own use of the personal data received through such sites

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

Shiksha.com reserves the right to update, change or modify this policy at any time. The policy shall come to effect from the date of such update, change or modification. 

## Disclaimer

Shiksha.com shall not be liable for any loss or damage sustained by reason of any disclosure (inadvertent or otherwise) of any information concerning the user's account and / or information relating to or regarding online transactions using credit cards / debit cards and / or their verification process and particulars nor for any error, omission or inaccuracy with respect to any information so disclosed and used whether or not in pursuance of a legal process or otherwise. Shiksha.com does not store any Credit / Debit card details.

Any other personal information shared by you which is not asked by Shiksha.com during registration, either mandatorily or optionally; accounts to wilful and intentional furnishing; and Shiksha.com will not be liable for breach of such information. 

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy or the protection of your personal data, please contact IEIL’s Data Protection Officer at the following:

**Data Protection Officer/ Grievance Officer**

IEIL (India) Limited

Noida GF-12A, Meghdoot, Nehru Place, New Delhi
